A Guide to the Vest Family Papers, 1866-1887
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Vest Family Papers, 1866-1887.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 91.17
12 items.
Vest family.; George S. Vest.; William W. Vest.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 1991.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence of George S. Vest of Williamsburg to Mary Garrett Vest before and after their marriage. Also letters of W.W. Vest to Mary Garrett Vest Watkins after the death of George S. Vest and her remarriage. Letters concern personal matters relating to courtship and daily events with some scattered mention of Williamsburg. Letters of W.W. Vest concern the education of his grandsons (sons of George S. Vest, George and Walter Vest) at the Virginia Military Institute.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Persons:
Watkins, Mary G.; Vest family.; Vest, George S.; Vest, William W.; Vest, Walter.
Subjects:
Courtship--Virginia--Williamsburg--History--19th century.; Education--Virginia--History--19th century.
Corporate Names:
Virginia Military Institute.
Contents List
- George S. Vest, Williamsburg, to Mary Garrett, 27 April 1866.
- George S. Vest, Williamsburg, to Mary Garrett, 28 May 1866.
- George S. Vest, Williamsburg, to Mary Garrett. Reacts to Mary's comments on his bad spelling by suggesting their engagement be broken off if she thinks he's not her social equal, 14 June 1866.
- George S. Vest, Williamsburg, to Mary Garrett, 17 June 1867.
- George S. Vest to Mary Garrett. Describes a dream in which an Angel stabs herself, 19 July 1867.
- [George S. Vest], Williamsburg to Mary Garrett, 28 July 1867.
- George S. Vest, Richmond, to Mrs. M. Vest, 20 August 1869.
- George S. Vest, Louisa County, to Mrs. George S. Vest [Mary Vest]. Mentions attending Baptisms. Responds to Mary's wish about moving "mammy" to Williamsburg, 5 September 1869.
- George S. Vest, Williamsburg, to his wife, Mary Vest. Has authorized Mr. Bouldin of Danville, a land agent, to sell her farm on the Bannister River, 6 October 1869.
- W.W. Vest, Williamsburg, to Mary Watkins (Mary Garrett Vest). At this time George S. Vest is dead and Mary has remarried. Concerns careers for his grandsons, George and Walter. Suggests they alter plans for railroad work or college and take up farming, 15 February 1887.
- W.W. Vest, Williamsburg, to George Vest (son of George S. Vest). Concerns educating George and his brother, Walter Vest at the Virginia Military Institute, 5 May 1887.
- W.W. Vest, Williamsburg, to Mary Watkins. Concerns the entrance of George and Walter Vest into the Virginia Military Institute, 25 May 1887.